《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously, on "Arrow"...
今晚我们齐心协力
Tonight we rise up as one
夺回这座城市
and take back this city.
斯莱德还有二十个跟他一样的人
Slade's got 20 guys just like him,
我们没办法阻止他
and we have no way to stop him.
米拉库鲁  我们要用它制造解药
Mirakuru. We're going to use it to make a cure.
斯莱德承诺让我当市长
Slade promised me city hall,
他兑现了这个承诺
and he delivered.
我知道他也向你作出过承诺
I understand he made you a promise, too.
这件事结束之前  还有一个人必须得死
There is still one person who has to die.
他们人太多了  我们打不过
There's so many of them! We can't fight!
不需要
We're not going to.
劳蕾尔
Laurel.
Laurel?
劳蕾尔
Laurel!
你杀了我
You killed me...
我来还你一个人情
let me return the favor.
你杀不了我
You can't kill me.
你并非不可战胜
You're not invincible.
差不多了
Close enough.
劳蕾尔
Laurel!
奥利弗
Oliver!
你还好吗
Are you OK?
隧道塌了
The tunnel collapsed.
我被困住了
I'm trapped.
我只是
I just...
越来越
It's getting really...
难以呼吸了
hard to breathe!
你会没事的
You are going to be OK.
把你能看见的东西都告诉我
I need you to tell me everything that you see.
石头  水  还有
Rocks, and water, and--
还有你的弓
and your bow.
看到我的箭袋了吗
You see my quiver?!
等等  是的  我拿到了
Wait! Yeah, yes, I have it! I have it.
里面还有多少支箭
How many arrows are in it?
有好几支
There's a bunch of them.
里面应该有一支箭是金属箭头
There should be one with a metallic head
比其它箭头都大
that's bigger than the rest of them.
看到了吗
Do you see it?
这个有什么用
Why do I need this?
因为这个是爆破箭头
Because it's an explosive arrow.
你得用它
And you're going to fire it.
你能帮我省点时间和精力吗
Do you want to save me some time and energy?
告诉我费利西蒂·斯莫克在哪里
Then tell me where I can find Felicity Smoak.
从那时候起  我一直很想朝她那张
I have been aching to put a bullet
自以为是的小脸上开一枪
in her smug little face ever since the day...
我还以为气囊要弹出来呢
I really thought the airbags were going to go off.
谢谢帮忙
Thanks for the help.
有奥利弗的消息吗
Any word from Oliver?
狄格
Dig...
你想怎么做  再撞她一下吗
What do you think, hit her again?
快开  快开
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
武器室
未经允许  禁止入内
出去  出去
Get out! Get out!
市政厅
市长办公室  星城中心区地检署
全城的记者都在赶来
Reports are coming in from all over the city.
星城总院正在准备接收伤者
Starling General is preparing for possible casualties.
军队已经从港湾大道南部出发了
Power is out south of Harbor Boulevard.
州长  州长
Governor. Governor.
这种时候派出国民警卫队
Sending in the national guard at this point
只会造成更大的恐慌
will only cause mass hysteria.
请相信我和我的警察
Trust me and my police force.
我们能够控制局面
We have this situation under control.
-市长先生  -斯宾塞地检官
- Mr. Mayor. - D.A. Spencer.
发生了什么事
What is going on?
有一群带面具的人在城市里到处破坏
There are men in masks tearing through the city.
是的  我知道  我们正在努力控制局面
Yes, I know. And we're doing everything we can.
星城一片混乱
星城警署的警力已经全部出动
The SCPD have already mobilized.
不  那些警察处理不了这种情况
No, the police force, they're not equipped to handle this.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我从来没见过这种状况
I have never seen anything like this before.
这些  戴面具的人
These--the men in masks,
简直  简直就不是人类
It--it's like they're not human.
不是人类
Not human?
凯特  你知道你在说什么吗
Kate, do you even hear yourself?
听着  我知道你很害怕
Look, I know you're scared,
但你得冷静下来
But you need to pull yourself together.
星城需要我们两个都能冷静思考
Starling City needs both of us thinking clearly right now.
为什么你这么冷静
How are you so calm?
星城一片混乱
因为我知道我们能够度过这一关
Because I know we're going to get through this.
当我们挺过来以后
And when we do,
星城会比以往更强大更美好
Starling City will be stronger and better for it.
我能依靠你吗
Can I count on you?
我需要你和我携手作战
I need you with me on this.
很好
Good.
那么让我们一起拯救城市
Then let's save the city together.
星城一片混乱
你离爆破点够远了吗
Are you far enough away from the debris to avoid the blast?
我不知道
I don't know!
如果我射不了那么远呢
What if I can't shoot that far?
那把弓是复合材质的  劳蕾尔
The bow's a hybrid compound, Laurel.
它完全能够做到
It's going to do all the work for you.
你需要做的只是
All I need you to do...
瞄准瓦砾的正中间
just aim at the middle of the debris.
深呼吸
Take a deep breath.
重心放在两脚之间
Center your feet.
左手握住弓
Left hand on the bow.
把箭放到弓弦上
Place the arrow on the drawstring.
我能行  我能行
OK, OK, OK, OK, OK.
好了  现在
All right, I want you to pull back
拉开弓弦
on the drawstring.
左臂伸直
And keep your left arm straight.
行了吗
OK?
数到三
You count to three
然后放箭的
and then you just let go.
你能做到
You can do this.
1, 2...
3!
射得漂亮
Nice shot.
狄格尔  能听见吗
Diggle, you there?
是的  奥利弗  我们听到了
Yeah, Oliver, we hear you.
我们要出来了
We're coming up.
莎拉不见了
Sara's gone.
一定是被斯莱德抓走的
Slade must have taken her.
该死[俄语]
Chert.
那是什么
What's that?
是声纳  我在监视亚马逊号
It's sonar. I was monitoring the "Amazo".
她在移动
She's moving.
我们还剩一个鱼雷  是吧
We have one torpedo left, right?
是的
Da.
你能让它沿直线射出去吗
Could you rig it to fire in a straight line?
我在探索我究竟能做多少
I'm discovering capacity to do many things
我从未想过能做的事
I never thought I would do.
我要你尽可能将潜艇靠近货船
I need you to get the sub close enough to the freighter
这样我能游过去
so that I can swim over.
那你需要鱼雷做什么
Well, then, what do you need torpedo for?
如果一个小时内我和莎拉还没回来
If Sara and I aren't back in an hour...
你就要击沉亚马逊号
you're going to sink the "Amazo".
不许动
Freeze!
你是谁
Who are you?
我是她爸爸
I'm her father.
绿箭
第二季  第二十二集
爸爸
Dad!
劳蕾尔  感谢上帝
Laurel, thank God.
你没事吧
Are you safe?
现在没事了
I am now.
我现在和绿箭在一起
I'm with the Arrow.
那  那就好
Well, that's-- that's good.
听着  我想他还有事要去处理
Now listen, something tells me he's got work to do.
-我要你避开大路  -好的
- I want you off the streets. - Yeah.
劳蕾尔  一定要保持低调
Laurel, please, keep low,
避人耳目  好吗
keep out of sight, all right?
爸爸  我知道了  你不必  担心我
Dad, I know, you don't have to worry...about me.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You OK?  - Yeah.
你呢
You?
伊莎贝尔袭击了狄格
Isabel attacked dig
所以我用面包车撞了她
so I hit her with the van.
是斯莱德的军队
Slade's army.
他至少派出了五十个和他一样的人
He has at least 50 men out there, all like him.
他们无处不在
They're everywhere.
我们要阻止他们
We need to stop them.
我可能有办法
We might have a way.
尖端科技研究实验室打来电话
S.T.A.R. Labs called.
他们有解药了  传递员已经在路上了
They have a cure. There's a courier en route.
到哪了
Where is it?
尖端科技研究实验室
费利西蒂
来电
喂
Hello?
我是费利西蒂·斯莫克  你在哪里
Hey, it's Felicity Smoak. Where are you?
我想是在第四大街  我不知道发生了什么
Fourth street, I think. I don't know what happened.
突然冒出一个戴曲棍球面罩的人
A guy in a hockey mask came out of nowhere
袭击了我的卡车
and attacked my truck.
-请救救我  -在那里等着
- Please help me. - Stay where you are.
我想动也动不了
I can't move even if I wanted to.
我觉得我腿断了
I think my leg's broken.
你该去了
You should go.
劳蕾尔  我不会半途抛下你走的
Laurel, I'm not leaving you out here in the middle of this.
我去警局  是往另一个方向走的
The precinct, it's in the other direction.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
劳蕾尔
Laurel,
不行
no.
我现在不需要你
I don't need you right now.
但其他人需要你
Everyone else does.
去吧
So go.
去拯救这个城市
Go save the city.
喂  你还在吗
Hey! You still there?
是的  我在  我已经标记了你的电话
Yeah, I'm here. I pinged your phone.
我们来了
On our way.
请快点
Please hurry.
找到他
Find him.
在过去五分钟里
In the last five minutes,
星城警署收到超过200份
SCPD has had over 200 reports
面具男袭击城市的报告
of masked men attacking the city.
我应该和劳蕾尔一起去
Should have gone with Laurel
确保她能够到达警局
and made sure she got to the precinct.
她会和她爸爸在一起的  不会有事的
She'll be with her father, she'll be fine.
奥利弗  她不会有事的
She will, Oliver.
好了
All right.
我们离货船十米远
We are 10 meters away from the freighter.
但这还是太疯狂了[俄语]
But still, this is sumasshedshiy.
太疯狂了  你都不确定她是否在威尔逊那
Crazy. You cannot even be certain that Wilson has her.
阿纳托利  你是个好人
You're a good man, Anatoly.
如果这是永别  那么请多保重
If this is good-bye, be safe.
我会很快再见到你和莎拉的
I will see you soon. You and Sara.
我说过了
I meant what I said.
如果我们一个小时内没回来
If we're not back in an hour,
你就击沉货船然后自己回家
you sink the freighter and get yourself home.
我觉得我可能更喜欢回巴哈马
I think maybe I prefer Bahamas.
奥利弗
Oliver.
我不知道我们能否再见
I don't know if we will see each other again.
但你要知道咱俩是永远的朋友
But know that you have made friend for life.
只要你有什么需要  无论是什么
If there is anything you need, it does not matter what...
你尽管开口
you have only to ask.
保重[俄语]  我的朋友
Prochnost, my friend.
包 包重
Proch...prochnost.
保重  保  我还要教你俄语
Prochnost...proch... I also teach you to speak Russian.
听着  我们要在
Listen up. We're going to establish a perimeter
第五大街和亚当斯街交汇点
with check-points at 5th and Adams,
第二大街和金斯利街交汇点设立检查站
2nd and Kingsley.
我们得创建一个安全区  听懂了吗
We got to create a safe zone, you hear me?
这些人到底是谁
Who the hell are these guys?
这些人是敌人
These guys are the enemy.
他们肆意伤害无辜群众
They're attacking innocents at random,
到处袭击  引发混乱
creating mayhem and chaos.
我们要去干掉他们
We need to put them down.
-副队  -现在就去
- Lieutenant... - Now!
听我说  你见过这些人吗
Listen to me, these guys, have you seen them?
你见过他们吗  他们是干不掉的
You seen these guys? They do not go down!
我们得叫来国民警卫队
We got to call in the National Guard.
那是市长的工作
That's a call for the Mayor.
但是他还没有这么做
And he hasn't made that yet.
他不会这么做的
And he won't.
这次事件是布拉德市长发起的
Mayor Blood let this happen.
-什么  -相信我
- What? - Trust me.
幕后主使是布拉德
Blood's behind this.
即使我相信你
Look, even if I believe you...
我没那么大权力
I don't have that kind of authority.
在紧急情况下  警察局长有这个权力
Well, in an emergency, the chief of police does,
快联系他
so get him on the line.
局长死了
Chief's dead.
这样的话
Well, then...
只有一个人可以帮我们了
there's only one more guy we can call.
但你不会喜欢的
You're not going to like it.
治安维持者
The vigilante.
绿箭
The Arrow.
副队
Lieutenant,
我知道他违反了法律
I know he's breaking the law.
但我们现在面对的局面
But what we're up against,
已经不是违法问题了  这关乎生死存亡
it's not about the law. It's about survival.
现在一群蒙面人肆意践踏我们的城市
We got masks tearing our city to pieces,
我们需要另一个蒙面人来阻止他们
and we're going to need a mask to stop 'em.
联系他吧
Make the call.
那好
Ok, let's do it.
还有件事
One more thing--
对眼下的局面  你比我所有手下了解得都多
You know more about what's going on over everyone else I got.
我把决策权交给你  你来指挥这些人
I need you making decisions and leading these men...
警探
Detective.
跟我来  我带你去安全的地方
Follow me. I can get you to safety.
莎拉
Sara...
我们派驻街头的记者已经失去联系
We lost contact with our reporter on the streets,
市政厅
但已经有数十名目击者证实这群蒙面人
but we have over two dozen confirmed sightings of masked men
在市内多个地点大肆破坏
attacking numerous municipal locations.
官方要求观众朋友尽量待在室内
Officials are asking that you stay indoors...
等等
Wait.
-住手  -别  不要
- Stop! - No, no, no!
够了
Enough!
计划不是这样的
This isn't part of the plan!
塞巴斯蒂安
Sebastian?!
我是星城市长
I am mayor of Starling City,
我命令你立即放开她
and I order you to let her go.
我不听命于你
I don't take orders from you.
糟了
No...
有西娅的消息吗  她安全吗
Any word from Thea? Is she safe?
在星城被袭之前
She decided to leave Starling
她就决定离开这里了
before the attacks started.
离大桥  还有运送人员不到两英里了
Just under two miles to the bridge. And the courier.
打给你的
It's for you.
怎么了  警探
What is it, Detective?
-需要我们做什么  -我们
- How can we help you? - We?
星城所有警察力量
The Starling City Police Force
将全力协助你应对这场危机
is standing with you on this one.
我需要你们协助遏制这些蒙面人
We need help containing the soldiers.
我们正在想办法
We're working something
阻止他们  但我们需要更多时间
and it may stop them but we need more time.
交给我们  不管你打算做什么  祝你好运
We can do that. Whatever you're doing, good luck.
祝我们所有人好运
For all our sakes.
想开上桥去只能走这条路
This is the only street that feeds into the bridge.
全速冲过去
Floor it!
小心
Hold on!
狄格
Dig?
狄格尔
Diggle!
我在这
Yeah, yeah.
她还有呼吸吗
Is she breathing?
-费利西蒂  -她还有呼吸
- Felicity! - Yeah, yeah.
我们得抓紧离开
Then we have to get out of here.
明白
Yeah, I'm on it.
西娅
Thea!
我不是来伤害你的
I'm not here to hurt you.
我凭什么相信你
Why should I believe you?
你是个杀人犯
You're a murderer!
是个恐怖分子  还是个疯子
Terrorist, and psychopath!
我并不指望你能理解我的所作所为
I don't expect you to understand what I've done.
现在不会
Not now.
因为我需要更多时间解释
Not without more time to explain.
你怎么可能还活着
How are you even alive?
你来干什么
Why are here?
我听说了你母亲的事
I heard what happened to your mother.
我需要来确保你的安全
I needed to make sure you were all right.
我需要见到我的女儿
I needed to see my daughter.
我不是你的女儿
I am not your daughter!
对我你什么都不是
You're nothing to me!
我完全不需要你
And I want nothing from you.
你听明白了吗
Do you understand?
明白  但现在
Yes. But right now,
你需要我的帮助
you need my help.
需要我的保护
My protection.
你完全不知道现在外面有多危险  西娅
You have no idea, Thea, how dangerous it is out there.
城市正在崩溃  让我带你去安全的地方吧
The city is falling. At least let me take you to safety.
传说暴君尼禄
They say Nero sang
对着一片火海的罗马城高声欢歌
as he watched Rome burn.
现在我明白他的感受了
Now I understand why.
要是莎朵能亲眼看到这一切就好了
If only Shado were here to witness this.
莎朵是谁
Who's Shado?
到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
你手下有个打了药的
Once of your juiced-up
神经病杀手杀了我办公室里的所有人
jack boots just killed my entire office staff,
还扭断了地区检察官的脖子
and snapped the district attorney's neck!
-然后呢  -然后
- And? - And...
我们之前可不是这么说的
And I never agreed to this!
你本来应该叫你的人收手的
You were supposed to call off your dogs.
那是你的计划  布拉德先生  不是我的
That was your plan, Mr. Blood, not mine.
我们有协议
We had a deal.
你是担心我不能履行约定吗
And do you feel that I've not lived up to my end of it?
外面死伤惨重的
Those are innocent people,
都是无辜的平民
dying out there.
你没必要连他们也杀
You do not need to kill them.
当然有必要
Yes, I do!
我曾对一个人立下重誓
I made a promise to someone once,
而我言出必践
and I will uphold it.
所以你筹划这一切
So this really is all about you
真的只是为了伤害奥利弗·奎恩
just trying to hurt Oliver Queen.
我曾对他发誓
I vowed to him
我会夺走他珍视的一切东西
that I would take away everything
杀死所有他爱的人
and everyone he loves.
而他爱这座城市
And he loves this city.
但这座城市
But this city...
也是我的城市
It's mine, too.
不再是了
Not anymore.
到了明天晚上
As of tomorrow night,
这里就只剩下碎石  灰烬和死亡
it'll be nothing but rubble, ash, and death.
到时候这里将变成再好不过的
A land only good for one thing.
坟墓
Graves.
莎拉
Sara...
你去哪里了
Where have you been?
这不重要
Doesn't matter.
你为什么回来
Why did you come back?
我不知道
I don't know.
这里没有属于我的东西
There isn't anything here for me.
你的家在这里
Your family's here.
劳蕾尔  你不了解我
You don't know, Laurel, about me.
你不知道我是谁  我变成了什么样子
About who I am and who I've become.
我只知道你是个英雄
I know you're a hero.
我不是英雄
I'm not a hero...
劳蕾尔
Laurel.
我根本就不是什么英雄
I am the furthest thing from it.
我是塔尔·莎菲尔
I am "Ta-er Sah-fer."
这是我的新名字
That was my new name.
因为曾经的那个女人
Because the woman that I was...
曾经的那个女孩
the girl that I was,
已经不见了
was gone.
我不会假装我和你有过
I'm not going to pretend that I've been through
同样的经历
anything that you have.
去年我学到的一件事
One thing that I've learned in the past year
就是我们的经历
is that these things...
不会击垮我们
they don't break us.
他们造就了我们
They make us who we are.
而我...已经无可救药了
And what I am... is irredeemable.
你刚刚说的是什么
What was that word you said before?
塔尔·莎菲尔
Ta-er Sah-fer.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是""金丝雀"."
It means "The Canary."
要是你早就丧失了本性
If you're so far gone
而且无可救药
and so irredeemable...
你为什么会有这么美丽的名字呢
then why would they know you by such a beautiful name?
奥利  奥利
Ollie! Ollie!
奥利  奥利  奥利  谢天谢地
Ollie, Ollie, Ollie! Thank God!
奥利  奥利
Ollie, Ollie...
跟我来
Come with me.
来  跟我来
All right, come with me.
这个潜艇就在货船旁边
The sub is right alongside the freighter.
你游过去就可以了
You just need to swim, OK?
好
OK.
你怎么还不走
OK, what are you doing?
我还不能走
I can't leave yet.
奥利  走吧
Ollie, come on.
-解药  -不
- The cure. - No!
我不能把斯莱德留下
I can't--I can't leave Slade behind.
我不能  就这么丢弃他
I'm not just going to-- I'm not just going to write him off.
是我们给他打的米拉库鲁
We injected him with the Mirakuru.
是我打的  奥利
But it was me-- Ollie.
我为了你放弃了莎朵
I chose you over Shado.
我  我只想回家
I--I just--I just want to go home.
我只想见到我的家人  奥利
I just want to see my family, Ollie.
我不想死
Please, I don't want to die.
走吧  求你了
Come on, please!
我必须这么做
I need to do this.
我要救回我的朋友
I need to save my friend.
我至少得试一试
I need to at least try.
到潜艇里去
Get to the sub.
保护自己
Get safe.
没有你我就不去了
Not without you.
莎拉
Sara...
走吧
Come on.
是爸爸
It's dad.
喂
Hello?
劳蕾尔  你在哪里
Laurel, baby, where are you?
55街和阿尔弗雷德路口  这有几个路障
55th and Alfred-- there were a few roadblocks.
你没事吧
But you're OK?
没事  莎拉和我在一起
Yeah. Sara's with me.
好  你们两个都待在原地
Right. Ok. Listen, stay there, both of you.
我马上过去
I'm on my way.
-我能自己走  -他在哪里
- I can walk. - Where is he?
手机定位显示他在500尺半径以内
The cell phone GPS says he should be within a 500-foot radius.
我打给他
I'll call him.
你在哪里
Hey, where are you?
我们到了  你在哪  按下喇叭
We're here, where are you? Honk your horn.
好  等下
Cool. Hold on.
等等  我看到你的脚了
Wait! I can see your feet.
你就在我车旁了
You're standing right outside my car.
那不是我们
That's not us.
不
Oh, no!
东西没了
It's gone.
当前情势非常紧张
The situation has intensified
当局正在全力控制
as officials struggle to contain
这次前所未见的对我市的攻击
this historic assault gripping our city.
威尔逊先生  这是你要的东西吗
Mr. Wilson, is this what you're looking for?
对  就是这个
Yes, it is.
我刚跟星级实验室的西斯科通过电话
I just got off the phone with Cisco at S.T.A.R. Labs...
他们送过来的是全部的解药
The cure they sent us was all they had.
而且他们用完了我们给的米拉库鲁
And they used all the Mirakuru that we gave them,
所以他们没办法再做了
so they can't make more.
没有解药我们就没法阻止斯莱德的人
We can't stop Slade's men without the cure.
我们会找到其他方法的
We'll find another way.
没有其他方法
There is no other way!
狄格尔  铸造厂被占领了
Diggle, the foundry's been compromised
我们得把罗伊救出来
and we need to get Roy out of there.
我现在就去
I'm on it.
我不知道  费利西蒂
I didn't know, Felicity.
五年前  我和现在完全不同
Five years ago, I was a completely different person.
我从来...
And I had...
不知道竟然会...
no idea that something like this was even...
发生这种事  我想象不到
possible. I couldn't have imagined.
你和狄格尔找我回星城的时候
When you and Diggle brought me back to Starling City,
我对我自己发誓  绝对不会
I made a vow to myself that I would never let anything
让爆炸惨剧之类的事再次发生
like the undertaking happen again.
现在发生的一切都不是你的错
What's happening now is not your fault.
不  这是我的错
Yes, it is.
我辜负了这座城市
I have failed this city.
辜负了姚飞
Yao Fei.
莎朵  汤米
Shado. Tommy.
我父亲  我母亲
My father, my mother.
我只是想缅怀这些人
All that I have ever wanted to do is honor those people.
那你就要继续战斗下去
You honor the dead by fighting.
你的战斗还没有结束
And you are not done fighting!
马尔科姆·梅林
Malcolm Merlyn,
伯爵  同步信号之王
the Count, the Clock King,
三合会  每一个想要伤害这座城市的人
The Triad--everyone who is trying to hurt this city,
都被你阻止了
you stopped them.
所以你也会阻止斯莱德的
And you will stop Slade.
-我不知道该怎么做  -我也不知道
- I don't know how. - Neither do I.
但我知道两件事
But I do know two things.
你不是一个人在战斗
You are not alone.
而且我相信你能做到
And I believe in you.
爸爸在哪  他现在应该到了
Where's dad? He should be here by now.
你应该去个更有利的位置
You should get to a better vantage point.
来人啊  救命啊
Somebody help! Please, help!
待在这别动
Stay here.
来人啊  救命啊
Someone help! Please help!
救命啊
Someone help!
救命
Please!
我女儿还在里面  我救不了她
My daughter is still inside, I couldn't get to her!
别去  太危险了
Don't, it's too dangerous!
-劳蕾尔  -爸爸
- Laurel! - Dad!
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
没有  我没事  我还好
No, I'm fine. I'm OK.
警员DC-52呼叫总部  请回复
Delta Charlie 52 to central, copy!
警员DC-52呼叫总部  请立即回复
Delta Charlie 52 to central, please copy me, now!
-警员DC-52呼叫总部  -爸爸
- Delta Charlie 52 to central... - Dad.
她没事
She's fine.
那是谁
Who was that?
她是金丝雀
That's the Canary.
西娅  求你了  跟我走
Thea, please, come with me.
我不想跟你有关系
I don't want anything to do with you.
我根本不想见到你
I don't want to even see you!
躲在我身后
Stay behind me.
你没有箭了
You're out of arrows.
你身上还有
You're not!
奥利弗
Oliver...
你的电话
this is your phone.
塞巴斯蒂安·布拉德
来电
你想怎么样
What do you want?
和你想的一样  奥利弗
Same thing you do, Oliver.
趁还来得及  拯救这座城市
To save this city before it's too late.
已经来不及了
It's already too late.
斯莱德·威尔逊的事被你说中了
You were right about Slade Wilson.
我之前应该听你的
I should have listened to you.
但我已经来了  我能帮助你
But I'm here now and I can help you.
我凭什么相信你
Why should I trust you?
因为  奥利弗
Because, Oliver...
我有米拉库鲁的解药
I have the Mirakuru cure.
剩下的毒药能让他昏迷多长时间
How much venom do we have to keep him under?
大约两个小时
Two hours, maybe.
走吧
Let's go.
我需要你陪着罗伊
I need you to stay with Roy.
好的
OK.
奥利弗  约翰
Oliver, John...
我多一句嘴
maybe this is obvious,
你们确定这不是圈套吗
but are we sure this isn't a trap?
不确定
No.
我得说一句  要是你们不能活着回来
I'm just saying, if you guys don't come back alive,
我会非常生气的
I'm going to be really pissed.
我小时候经常被噩梦困扰
As a young boy, I was plagued by nightmares.
每天晚上我都会惊醒
Every night, I would wake up
浑身冒冷汗  感到害怕和孤独
in a cold sweat, frightened and alone.
我一直忘不掉我父亲那张脸
It was my father's face that haunted me.
这就是他在我眼中的样子
And this is how I saw him.
简直就是绝望的化身
The embodiment of desperation and despair.
我做这个面具是为了克服我的恐惧
I made this mask to conquer my fears.
提醒自己为什么要战斗
And remind myself why I fight,
那就是每一天
every day,
都要给这座城市最绝望的人一个机会
to give this city's most desperate a chance.
奥利弗  我只是想帮助别人
All I ever wanted to do was help people, Oliver.
那你就拿出实际行动来
Then help me believe.
解药在哪里
Where is the cure?
斯莱德·威尔逊在兑现
Slade Wilson will not rest
他对你的承诺之前  绝不会罢休
until he honors the promise that he made you.
只要我们实力相当  他很难杀死我
I won't be so easy to kill once we level the playing field.
他还不想杀你
He's not interested in killing you.
除非他已经夺走了一切
Not until he's taken away
你所爱的人和物
everything and everyone you love.
他杀死我母亲后
After he murdered my mother,
他说还有一个人要死
he said one more person had to die.
肯定是你最爱的人
Whoever you love the most.
我希望你能用这个打败他
I hope you can beat him with this.
为了我们所有人
For all our sakes.
等这一切都结束了  我向你保证
And when this is over, I promise you...
我会尽我所能  重建星城
I will do everything in my power to rebuild Starling City.
而且我不仅会让它恢复原貌
And I won't just make it what it was.
还会让它变得更好
I will make it better.
就像我一直计划的那样
Like I always planned.
你真的以为
You really think...
在发生了这一切之后
after everything that's happened,
就凭你的这些所作所为
after what you've done,
人们还会继续让你当市长吗
that they'll still let you be mayor?
为什么不
Why not?
他们只知道我在尽力挽救这座城市
No one knows that I've done anything except try to save this city.
如果你告诉别人我那面具的事
And if you tell anyone about my mask,
我也会把你的事抖出来
I will tell them about yours.
做好你该做的事  塞巴斯蒂安
Do what you have to, Sebastian.
我得回去了
I got to get back to it.
你们没事吧
Hey. Are you guys OK?
你有没有事
Are you OK?
简直难以置信  一个戴面具的金发女子
You wouldn't believe it-- a blonde in a mask
抱着个孩子冲出了大火熊熊的建筑物
ran out of a burning building with a kid in her arms.
真是太勇敢了  那个女人是个英雄
It was the bravest thing I've ever seen. That woman's a hero.
你给他了对不对
You gave it to him, didn't you?
我觉得有这个必要
I did what I thought was necessary.
不用担心  我会跟斯莱德说
Don't worry, I'll tell Slade.
他手里还有解药吗
Does he still have the cure?
没有
No.
斯莱德  你背叛了...
Slade, you betrayed--
永别了  布拉德先生
Good-bye, Mr. Blood.
我爱过这座城市
I loved this city.
为什么所有秘方都有颜色
Why does every secret formula have to be a color?
历史悠久的无色都哪里去了
Whatever happened to good, old-fashioned clear?
如果我们给斯莱德的战士注射这个...
All right, so if we inject one of Slade's soldiers with this...
根据星级实验室的研究
According to S.T.A.R. Labs,
这个会抵消米拉库鲁的药效
it will counteract the effects.
前提是他们的配方正确
Assuming they got the recipe right.
我们得先测试一下
We need to test it.
不行
We can't.
要把罗伊当做实验小白鼠吗
Treat Roy like some kind of lab rat?
费利西蒂
Felicity...
要是不起作用呢
What if it doesn't work?
要是把他害死了呢
What if it kills him?
要是他醒来把我们杀了呢
What if he wakes up and kills us?
我们总得想办法知道
We need to know. One way or the other.
去把另一扇门关上
Go lock the other door.
好
OK.
莎拉  艾沃的保险箱在哪里
Sara, where does Ivo keep his safe?
在...  他的书边上
It's, uh, by his books.
奥利弗
Oliver...
你找什么呢  小子  这个吗
What are you looking for, kid? This?
兰斯警探
Detective Lance.
什么事
Yeah?
发生什么事了
What's going on?
怎么了
What is it?
现在直播的是
You're watching live footage
一支护航军队
of an army convoy arriving
抵达星城外郊准备恢复城市秩序
on the outskirts of the city to restore order.
装甲部队终于来了
Looks like the cavalry's here, finally.
-可能吧  -什么意思
- Maybe. - What do you mean?
他们正在占领大桥和隧道
Well, they're taking up positions in the bridges and tunnels.
那是进城的唯一方法
Well, those are the only ways into the city.
对  也是出城的唯一方法
Yeah, and the only ways out.
我一个做军事情报的哥们
A buddy of mine in military intelligence
曾经跟我说军队并不总是军队
once told me the army isn't always the army.
但显然是军方
But it's clearly the military.
看他们的卡车  制服
The trucks, the uniforms.
但是最近的军事基地在市政局纪念厅
Except the nearest army base is at Monument Point,
离这里有300英里远
which is 300 miles from here.
所以他们怎么会这么快就到星城了呢
So how could they mobilize to Starling City so fast?
好吧  如果不是军队
OK. So if that isn't the army,
那到底是谁
who the hell are they?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我下不了手
I can't.
是兰斯  警探
It's Lance. Detective.
-他在吗  -在
- Are you near him? - Yes.
-你那边有电视吗  -有
- Are you near a TV? - Yes.
打开
Turn it on.
你怎么知道我这个号码的
How did you get this number?
阿曼达  你在干什么
Amanda. What are you doing?
我不懂你的意思  奥利弗
I'm not sure what you mean, Oliver.
阿曼达  那支部队占领了星城的出口...
Amanda, the troops taking up position at the city's exits--
他们不是军方的人  是超能力联合调查组
They're not army, they're A.R.G.U.S.
是你的人  所以你告诉我你到底想干什么
Those are your men. So you tell me what you're up to.
阿曼达
Amanda!
斯莱德的追随者明显
Slade's followers are a clear
是我们目前的威胁  我不能让他们
and present danger. I cannot allow them
逃出星城  得控制住他们...
to escape the city. They need to be contained...
不惜任何手段
by any means necessary.
你不能这样做
You can't.
现在正有一架无人机
There's a drone en route
带着六枚GBU/43-B炸弹过去
carrying six GBU/43-B bombs,
火力足以将星城夷为平地
enough fire power to level the city.
星城里还有50多万平民呢
There are over half a million people in this city.
57万6千人
576,000.
他们都是无辜的
None of whom deserve to die.
但我也得为其他城市的人考虑
But I have to think about the people in every city.
你说过米拉库鲁会让人变得坚不可摧
You once told me that Mirakuru made a man virtually unstoppable.
要是我不马上结束这件事
What could happen to this country,
那对我们国家
this world,
还有整个世界会有什么后果
if I don't end this here and now?
听我说
Listen to me.
我有解药
I have the cure.
我可以阻止斯莱德和他的人
I can stop Slade and his men.
万一失败了呢  我不能冒这个险  奥利弗
I can't take the chance you'll fail, Oliver.
阿曼达  求你多给我点时间
Amanda, I just need more time.
对不起
I'm sorry.
只能到黎明之前
You have until dawn.
否则星城就会成为一片废墟
And then Starling City is a crater.
你想开枪的话
If you're going to use that,
记得关掉保险
you'll want to click the safety off.
我会开枪的
I'll shoot you.
我会的
I will!
我可以从你眼中看到
I can see it in your eyes.
我的眼睛
My eyes.
你的眼睛跟我的一样
They're just like mine.
双眼中都充满了痛苦和愤怒
Both of them filled with pain and anger,
因为我们爱的人都被抢走了
because those we loved were ripped from us.
我失去了我的名字  我妻子
I lost my name, my wife...
汤米
Tommy.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你是这个世界上我唯一的亲人了
You're all I have left in this world,
你也失去了一切
and you've lost everything, too.
西娅
Thea.
但是你还有父亲
But you still have a father.
你还有...
You still have...